restaurantbusinessonline.com 2019-12-30

# Privacy Policy

_Updated and Effective as of December, 2018_

We have prepared this privacy policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) to explain to you how we collect, use, and share information and personally identifiable information (“ **Personal Data** ”) we obtain through your use of the Web sites, applications and online services, including Web sites, online services and applications related to or used in connection with our events (" **Services** ”) that are operated by, controlled by or affiliated with Winsight, LLC, including without limitation _Restaurant Business Online_ , _CSP Daily News_ , _FoodService Director_ , _Winsight Grocery Business_ , _Technomic_ and all related Web sites and digital entities (collectively, “ **Winsight** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **us** ,” or “ **our** ”).

This Privacy Policy only covers information collected through the Services between you and Winsight, and does not cover any information collected at any other Web site, application or otherwise by us (unless specifically stated), including when you call us, write to us, or communicate with us in any manner other than through the Services. By using the Services, you consent to such use of your information and Personal Data and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We will only process your Personal Data in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws. For the purposes of United Kingdom and European Union data protection legislation, the data controller is Winsight, LLC, 300 S. Riverside Plaza, Suite 1600, Chicago, IL, 60606.

* * *

 **TABLE OF CONTENTS**

  1.  _INFORMATION WE AUTOMATICALLY COLLECT_
  2.  _COOKIES/TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES_
  3.  _INFORMATION YOU CHOOSE TO SUBMIT_
  4.  _INFORMATION WE RECEIVE FROM OTHER SOURCES_
  5.  _INFORMATION USE_
  6.  _SOCIAL NETWORK AND PLATFORM INTEGRATION_
  7.  _OUR INFORMATION SHARING PRACTICES_
  8.  _ TECHNOMIC PAID RESEARCH AND SUBSCRIPTION_
  9.  _TECHNOMIC OPERATOR COMMUNITY PANEL_
  10.  _TECHNOMIC CONTACTS DATABASE_
  11.  _ANONYMOUS DATA_
  12.  _PUBLIC INFORMATION_
  13.  _IMPORTANT INFORMATION FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS - CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS_
  14.  _HOW WE RESPOND TO DO NOT TRACK SIGNALS_
  15.  _USERS OUTSIDE OF THE UNITED STATES AND CONSENT TO TRANSFER_
  16.  _IMPORTANT INFORMATION ON EUROPEAN UNION AND UNITED KINGDOM USER RIGHTS_
  17.  _ADVERTISING_
  18.  _CHOICE/OPT-OUT OF COMMUNICATIONS_
  19.  _MODIFYING AND DELETING YOUR PERSONAL DATA_
  20.  _SECURITY_
  21.  _LINKS_
  22.  _CHILDREN'S POLICY_
  23.  _SENSITIVE PERSONAL DATA_
  24.  _CHANGES_
  25.  _CONTACT US_

* * *

 **Information We Automatically Collect**

We and our third-party service providers (including any third-party content, advertising, and analytics providers) may automatically collect certain information from your device or web browser when you interact with the Services to help us understand how our users use the Services and to target advertising to you (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as “ **Usage Data** ”). For example, each time you visit the Services we and our third-party service providers may automatically collect your IP address, mobile device identifier or other unique identifier, browser and computer type, access time, the Web page you came from, the URL you go to next, the Web page(s) that you access during your visit and your interaction with content or advertising on the Services.

We and our third-party service providers may use such Usage Data for a variety of purposes including to diagnose problems with our servers and software, to administer the Services, to gather demographic information and to target advertising to you on the Services and elsewhere online. Accordingly, our third-party advertising networks and ad servers will also provide us with information, including reports that will tell us how many ads were presented and clicked on the Services in a manner that does not identify personally any specific individual. The Usage Data we collect is generally non-identifying, but if we specifically identify or associate it with you, we will treat it as Personal Data.

* * *

 **Cookies/Tracking Technologies**

We may use tracking technologies, such as cookies, local storage, and pixel tags as well as other similar technologies, such as web beacons, tags and scripts, including local storage objects such as HTML5 (“ **Tracking Technologies** ”). Tracking Technologies may set, change, alter or modify settings or configurations on your device.

 _Cookies and Local Storage_

Cookies and local storage may be set and accessed on your computer. Upon your first visit to the Services, a cookie or local storage may be sent to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. “ **Cookies** ” and local storage are small files containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer's browser and stored on your device when you visit a Web site. Many major Web services use cookies to provide useful features for their users. Each Web site can send its own Cookie to your browser. Most browsers are initially set up to accept Cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all Cookies or to indicate when a Cookie is being sent; however, if you reject Cookies, you will not be able to sign in to the Services or take full advantage of our Services. Additionally, if you clear all Cookies on your browser at any point after setting your browser to refuse all Cookies or indicate when a Cookie is being sent, you will have to again reset your browser to refuse all Cookies or indicate when a Cookie is being sent.

You can find more information about Cookies and how they work, what Cookies have been set on your computer or mobile device and how to manage and delete them at [_http://www.allaboutcookies.org/_](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and _www.youronlinechoices.com/uk_.

 _Pixel Tags_

We may also use “pixel tags,” which are small graphic files that allow us and third parties to monitor the use of the Services and collect Usage Data. A pixel tag can collect information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the tag appears; the URL of the page on which the pixel tag appears; the time (and length of time) the page containing the pixel tag was viewed; the type of browser that retrieved the pixel tag; and the identification number of any cookie previously placed by that server on your computer.

We may use pixel tags, either provided by us or by our third party advertisers, service providers and ad networks, to collect information about your visit, including the pages you view, the links you click and other actions taken in connection with our Web sites and Services and use them in combination with our Cookies to provide offers and information of interest to you. Pixel tags may also enable ad networks to serve targeted advertisements to you when you visit the Services or other web sites.

Web Beacons.

Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as “1x1 GIFs” or “clear GIFs”) may be included in the Service’s pages and messages. Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a page or e-mail can act as a web beacon. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to the Service, to monitor how users navigate the Service, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.

In addition, we may use a variety of other technologies that collect similar information for security and fraud detection purposes.

Tracking Technologies Usage.

We may use Tracking Technologies for a variety of purposes, including:

Strictly Necessary. We may use Cookies or other Tracking Technologies that we consider strictly necessary to allow you to use and access the Services, including Cookies required to prevent fraudulent activity and improve security.

 _Performance Related_. We may use Cookies or other Tracking Technologies that are useful in order to assess the performance of the Services, including as part of our analytic practices or otherwise to improve the content, products or services offered through the Services.

 _Functionality Related_. We may use Cookies or other Tracking Technologies that are required to offer you enhanced functionality when accessing the Services, including identifying you when you visit the Services or keeping track of your specified preferences, including in terms of the presentation of content on the Services.

 _Targeting Related_. We may use Tracking Technologies to deliver content relevant to your interests on the Services and third-party sites based on how you interact with our Services. This includes using Tracking Technologies to understand the usefulness to you of the content that has been delivered to you.

 _Tracking Technologies Choices and Consent_

We obtain your consent to our information storage or collection Tracking Technologies by providing you with transparent information in our Privacy Policy and providing you with the opportunity to make a choice to disable Cookies as set forth above. Please note that we are not required to obtain your consent to the information collection Tracking Technologies identified above that are strictly necessary.

We are giving you detailed notice of the Tracking Technologies and your limited choices regarding them so that your consent is meaningfully informed.

* * *

 **Information You Choose To Submit**

You can visit the Services without telling us who you are or revealing any Personal Data. If, however, you wish to register to become a member of the Services, you are required to provide certain Personal Data (for example, your name and e-mail address), and you must also provide a user name and password. You are responsible for keeping your user name and password secure and agree you will not to share your account with others. We use your Personal Data to fulfill your requests for products and services, to improve our Services, to contact you from time to time, with your consent, about us and our products and services, and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. You may also choose to submit or we may collect additional information about you, such as demographic information (for example your gender, birth date, or zip code) and information about your preferences and interests. We refer collectively to all information we collect that is not Personal Data, including Usage Data, demographic data and de-identified Personal Data, as “ **Non-Personal Data**.” If we combine Non-Personal Data with Personal Data, we will treat the combined information as Personal Data under this Privacy Policy. You also may choose to submit your alias, bio, email, photos or any other information that you would like to share with other users of the Services (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as “ **User Submissions** ”). Personal Data, Non-Personal Data, and User Submissions are referred to in this Privacy Policy collectively as “ **User Information**.”

* * *

 **Information We Receive From Other Sources**

We may supplement the information we collect with outside records in order to learn more about our users, to better tailor the content and offers we show you, and for other purposes. We may receive this information about you from third parties, including without limitation consumer data resellers and advertisers. We may combine the information we receive from those other sources with information we collect through the Services. In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to the combined information, including treating certain information as Personal Data.

* * *

 **Information Use**

We may use the information we collect, including Personal Data and Usage Data:

\- to enable you to use our Services, to create an account or profile, to process information you provide via our Services (including verifying that your email address is active and valid) and to process your transactions;

\- to provide related customer service and care, including responding to your questions, complaints, or comments and sending surveys (with your consent) and processing survey responses;

\- to fulfill paid subscription services and report back usage information to the subscribing corporation;

\- to provide you with information, products, or services that you have requested;

\- with your consent, to provide you with information, products, or services that we otherwise believe will interest you, including special opportunities from us and our third-party partners;

\- to tailor content, recommendations, and advertisements we and third parties display to you, both on the Services and elsewhere online;

\- for internal business purposes, such as to improve our Services;

\- to administer and process contests, sweepstakes, and promotions, provided that such contests, sweepstakes and promotions may carry their own separate terms of use and privacy policy, in which case those policies would further govern your participation;

\- to contact you with administrative communications and, in our discretion, changes to our Privacy Policy, Terms of Use, or any of our other policies;

\- to comply with regulatory and legal obligations; and

\- for purposes as disclosed at the time you provide your information, with your consent, and as further described in this Privacy Policy.

We may use and/or disclose your Personal Data or Usage Data for the following reasons:

  * to contact you in response to your inquiries, comments and suggestions;
  * to contact you when otherwise necessary;
  * for the specific purpose for which it was volunteered;
  * to track our visitors’ use of the Services for internal market research;
  * to improve our Web sites and the Services we promote or provide through the Web sites;
  * to customize the content and/or layout of our Web sites for each individual visitor;
  * to ask for your participation in brief surveys;
  * to complete any purchases or other transactions you may perform through the Services;
  * to notify visitors about updates to the Services;
  * to notify you about promotions, special offers, etc. regarding products and services provided by Winsight or its affiliates or partners;
  * to be provided to our affiliates or third parties in connection with the legitimate business purposes of Winsight or any affiliate;
  * to be provided to third parties for the legitimate business purposes of those third parties;
  * to generate aggregate statistical studies;
  * as required by law or regulation, or as requested by government authorities, or for the protection of persons or property;
  * in connection with an acquisition, merger, restructuring, sale or other transfer involving all or any portion of the business associated with the Services;
  * to report usage information to the subscribing employer corporation to inform product development/content planning and technical plans related to server capacity or similar;
  * to identify high-interest content by cohort to inform future content, product and development efforts of Winsight or any affiliates; and
  * for other legitimate business purposes.

We use reasonable security safeguards to protect the Personal Data that we collect from unauthorized access. Due to the nature of the Internet, however, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and our servers will be free from unauthorized access by third parties.

* * *

 **Social Network and Platform Integration**

The Services may contain integration with social networks and other platforms in which information is shared between us and such platforms (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, Twitter). For example, if you create or log into your account through a third-party social media site, we will have access to certain information from that site, such as your name, email address, account information, photo and friends lists, and other information in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by such social media site. If you visit our Services on a device through which you also interact with social networks or if you interact with us through a social media function such as a plug-in (for example, a Facebook "like" button) then you permit us to have on-going access to, to use and to store some information from your social network profile (such as your name, email address, your friend list, photo, age, gender, location, birthday, social networking ID, current city, and the people/sites you follow) in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you don't want a social network to collect the information about you as described above, or you don't want a social network to share it with us, please review the privacy policy, privacy settings and instructions of the applicable social network before you visit and use our Services. Please note that we are not responsible for the collection, use, maintenance, sharing, or disclosure of data and information by such social networks. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of websites that you visit so that you understand how they collect and use your information before using such websites.

* * *

 **Our Information Sharing Practice**

 ** _Generally_** **:** We may share Non-Personal Data, including Usage Data, de-identified Personal Data and aggregated user statistics, with third parties in our discretion. We may share User Information, including Personal Data, as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, and under the following circumstances:

 ** _Service Providers_** _:_ From time to time, we may enter into relationships with third parties who provide services to us (for example, analytics companies, advertisers and ad agencies, data management and storage services or credit card processing services, sweepstakes or contest prize fulfilment). In those circumstances, we disclose User Information so that such service providers may perform those services. These service providers are only permitted to use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to enable them to provide their services to us. They are required to follow our express instructions and to comply with appropriate security measures to protect your Personal Data. In particular, our sites use certain Google analytics and other services, and certain pages use the Google AMP Client ID API, each of which may enable collection and sharing of your information (including Personal Data) with Google for further use. For specific information on Google usage and how to control it, please see How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps and Google’s Privacy Policy.

 ** _Third Party Marketing:_** __  We may share your information (including Personal Data) with third parties for those third parties’ own direct marketing purposes. Messages delivered from a third party will subject you to the third party’s privacy policy. We may also match your email address with third parties with whom you have also consented to share your email address and use such match to deliver custom offers or emails to you.

In the event we go through a business transition (such as a merger, acquisition by another company, bankruptcy, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process), your Personal Data will likely be among the assets transferred. By providing your Personal Data, you agree that we may transfer such information in those circumstances without your further consent.

 _Other Disclosure Scenarios._ We reserve the right, and you hereby expressly authorize us, to share User Information: (1) in response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish, protect, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims; (2) if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, fraud, or situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or property; (3) if we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding significant abuse of the Services infrastructure or the Internet in general (such as voluminous spamming, denial of service attacks, or attempts to compromise the security of information); (4) to protect and defend our legal rights or property, our Services or other users, or any other party, and to protect the health and safety of our users or the general public; (5) to our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control with us (in which case we will require such entities to honor this Privacy Policy); (6) and whenever required by law.

* * *

 **Technomic Paid Research and Subscription Services**

Users of Technomic’s paid research products and services agree to this Privacy Policy and understand that access to these products and services is authorized through a paid agreement between their employer and the Company.   Any changes to the paid agreement may affect the products and services employee users may access.

To access online paid research products and services, employee users must validate their identities, create log in credentials, and provide certain information to create a profile in the system.

Employee users understand that the Company may disclose all digital behaviors collected when using these paid services to the employee’s employer, and for its own purposes related to analyzing usage and improving the quality of the Services.

* * *

 **Technomic Operator Community Panel**

If you are using Technomic Services, Technomic has created an Operator Community Panel that serves as a platform for qualified operators to participate in various discussions and surveys.  This Operator Panel Community is subject to a separate privacy policy that can be reviewed here. Note that any use by you of the Operator Panel Community is subject to the terms and conditions of that privacy policy.

* * *

 **Technomic Contact Databases**

If you are accessing Technomic Services, Technomic maintains databases of key personnel at industry related companies.  Technomic subscribers pay a fee to access these databases.  In some cases the contacts listed are a matter of public record and in other cases, contact information is discovered through research.  European Union and United Kingdom residents listed as a contact in one of these databases have rights as set forth below with respect to their personal information.

* * *

 **Anonymous Data**

When we use the term “ **Anonymous Data** ,” we are referring to de-identified Personal Data and Usage Data, either alone or when combined with any other information available to a third party. We may create Anonymous Data from the Personal Data we receive about you and other individuals whose Personal Data we collect. Anonymous Data might include analytics information and information collected by us using Cookies. We make Personal Data into Anonymous Data by excluding information (such as your name, address, e-mail) that makes the data personally identifiable to you.  We use this Anonymous Data to analyze usage patterns in order to make improvements to our Services.

* * *

 **Public Information**

If you identify any User Information as public, you are authorizing us to share such information publicly. For example, you may elect to make certain of your User Submissions (such as your alias, bio, email or photos) publicly available. Also, there may be areas of the Services (for example, message boards, discussion rooms, and other online forums) in which you are able to post information that automatically will be available to all other users of the Services. By choosing to use these areas, you understand and agree that anyone may access, use, and disclose any information that you post to those areas.

* * *

 **Important Information for California Residents-Your California Privacy Rights**

For purposes of California residents, this Privacy Policy pertains to all information collected online, including through this the Services. California law permits customers of Winsight who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

If you are a California resident and you have questions about our practices with respect to sharing information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes and your ability to exercise choice, please contact us at Winsight, LLC, Inc., c/o General Counsel, 300 S. Riverside Plaza, Suite 1600, Chicago, IL 60606. You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. In the body of your request, please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you. Please note that we will not accept inquiries via the telephone, email, or by facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labelled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information. This request may be made no more than once per calendar year. We further reserve our right not to respond to requests submitted to address other than the address specified in this paragraph.

* * *

 **How We Respond to “Do Not Track” Signals**

Some Internet browsers may be configured to send “Do Not Track” signals to the online services that you visit. California Business & Professions Code Section 22575(b) (as amended effective January 1, 2014) provides that California residents are entitled to know how Winsight responds to “Do Not Track” browser settings.

There currently is no consensus among industry participants as to what “Do Not Track” means in this context. Therefore, like many websites and online services, the Services do not alter their practices when they receive a “Do Not Track” signal from a visitor's browser. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” please visit _http://www.allaboutdnt.com_.

* * *

 **Users Outside of the United States and Consent to Transfer**

 The Services are operated in the United States. If you are located in another jurisdiction, please be aware that information you provide to us will be transferred to, stored and processed in the United States. By using the Services or providing us with any information, you consent to this transfer, processing, and storage of your information in the United States, a jurisdiction in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside or are a citizen. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

* * *

 **Important Information for European Union and United Kingdom User Rights**

If you are a user from the European Union or United Kingdom, you have certain rights and protections under the law regarding the processing of your personal information. You can view Winsight’s full Data Protection Policy for such European Union or United Kingdom users [here](http://cspdigitals.com/winsight/Data-Protection-Policy-Winsight-LLC-052318-AY.pdf).

As a brief summary, if you are a user from the European Union or the United Kingdom, upon request, you have the right to:

(a)        obtain a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you;

(b)       access the Personal Data we hold about you;

(c)        request information about the purposes of us processing your Personal Data and the categories of Personal Data concerned;

(d)       obtain information on the recipients or categories of recipients (including international recipients) to whom your Personal Data has been or will be disclosed;

(e)        request a transfer of your Personal Data from us to another data controller;

(f)        in certain circumstances, request the “right to be forgotten” and the erasure of all the Personal Data we hold about you;

(g)       lodge a complaint to the supervisory authority in your jurisdiction in respect of your data protection rights; and

(h)       withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us as set forth in this Privacy Policy, however please be aware that such withdrawal of consent will not affect the lawfulness of Personal Data collected, processed and transferred prior to the date of your withdrawal of consent.

There is no charge for any of these requests. For any such request please contact us at Winsight, LLC, 300 S. Riverside Plaza, Suite 1600, Chicago, IL, 60606, by phone at (312) 876-0004 or send us an email at inquire@winsightmedia.com. We will endeavor to respond to such requests in a timely manner, but in no event longer than one month.

When we collect your Personal Data, we will maintain and store it for as long as we determine reasonably necessary to provide the Services to you, unless you exercise your right to erasure described above, or to comply with applicable legal requirements.

 **Legal Basis for Processing**

If you are a citizen of the European Union or United Kingdom, when we process your Personal Data we will only do so in the following situations:

  * We need to use your personal information to perform our responsibilities to you or where required by law.
  * We have a legitimate interest in processing your Personal Data. For example, we may process your Personal Data to send you marketing communications, relevant content, products or events invitations, or to communicate with you about changes to our Services, and to provide, secure, and improve our Services.       

 **Questions or Complaints**

If you are user in the European Union or United Kingdom and have a concern about our processing of personal information that we are not able to resolve, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the data privacy authority where you reside. For contact details of your local Data Protection Authority, please see: http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm.

* * *

 **Advertising**

 ** _General:_** We may use other companies under agreements with us to serve third-party advertisements when you visit and use the Services. These companies may collect and use click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over during your visits to the Services and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use tracking technologies to collect this information. Other companies’ use of their tracking technologies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one.

 ** _Targeted Advertising:_** In order to serve offers and advertisements that may be of interest to our users, we may display targeted advertisements on the Services, or other digital properties or applications in conjunction with our content, based on information provided to us by our users and information provided to us by third parties that they have independently collected. User Information is sometimes provided to sponsors and advertisers as a result of interacting with their advertising, branded content or other products.

 ** _Your Ad Choices:_** Some of the third-party services providers and/or advertisers may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“ **NAI** ” or the Digital Advertising Alliance (“ **DAA** ”) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. You may want to visit [_http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp_](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp), which provides information regarding targeted advertising and the "opt-out" procedures of NAI members. You can opt-out of our use of your Web site viewing behavior data to serve you interest-based advertising on third-party sites and email newsletters here [_http://www.aboutads.info/choices/_](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

Please note opting out through these mechanisms does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads while online or on your device.

 ** _Mobile:_** We may from time to time offer certain location or pinpoint based services, such as location assisted navigation instruction. If you elect to use such location-based services, we must periodically receive your location in order to provide such location-based services to you. By using the location-based services, you authorize us to: (i) locate your hardware; (ii) record, compile and display your location; and (iii) publish your location to third parties designated by you by means of location publication controls available within the applications (for example, settings, user preferences). As part of the location-based services, we may also collect and store certain information about the users who elect to use such location-based services, such as a device id. This information will be used to provide you the location-based services. We may use third-party providers to help provide location-based services through mobile systems (unless you opt out of such location-based services with such providers) and we may provide the information to such providers to enable them to provide their location-based services, provided that such providers may use the information in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

* * *

 **Choice/Opt-Out From Communications**

We offer you the opportunity to manage your communications from us. Even after subscribing to one or more newsletters and/or opting in to one or more offers to receive marketing and/or promotional communications from us or our third party partners, users may elect to modify their preferences by going to the Communications Preferences page anytime or by following the "Communications Preferences" and/or "Unsubscribe" link provided in an email or communication received.

  *  _[CSP Daily News Communications Preference Center](mailto:onlinesupport@winsightmedia.com)_
  *  _[Restaurant Business Communications Preference Center](mailto:onlinesupport@winsightmedia.com)_
  *  _[FoodService Director Communications Preference Center](mailto:onlinesupport@winsightmedia.com)_
  *  _[Winsight Grocery Business Communications Preference Center](mailto:onlinesupport@winsightmedia.com)_
  * Technomic Opt-Out contact: [info@technomic.com](mailto:info@technomic.com).

You may also be able to change your preferences by updating your profile or account, depending on which of our Services you are using. Please be aware that if you wish to remove yourself from a newsletter and/or other marketing emails from third parties that you consented to through the Services, you must do so by contacting the relevant third-party. Even if you do opt-out of marketing emails, we reserve the right to send you transactional and administrative emails including those related to the Services, service announcements, notices of changes to this Privacy Policy or other Services policies, and to contact you regarding any goods or services you have ordered.

In some cases we will offer special content, products or services in exchange for an email address that might be used to share our various editorial or marketing products. Our sponsors and clients might make similar offers to our audiences via our digital products, in which case the email address will be shared with that client. We will make reasonable efforts to be transparent about that sharing when you offer your email address.

* * *

 **Modifying and Deleting Your Personal Data**

You may access the information we hold about you. If you wish to exercise this right, please contact us using the details in the Contact Us section below. If you would like to update, correct, modify or delete from our database any Personal Data you previously submitted to us, please let us know by accessing and updating your profile. If you delete certain information you may not be able to order services in the future without re-submitting such information. We will comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. Also, please note that we will maintain Personal Data in our database whenever we are required to do so by law.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting such change or deletion (for example, when you enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the Personal Data provided until after the completion of such promotion). We will retain your Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

* * *

 **Security**

We have implemented commercially reasonable security measures to help protect your Personal Data from loss, misuse, or unauthorized access or disclosure; unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your User Information, including Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its security. You use the Services and provide us with information at your own initiative and risk. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us using the details in the Contact Us section below.

* * *

 **Links**

The Services may contain links to other websites that we do not control, and the Services may contain videos, advertising and other content hosted and served by third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any third-party.

* * *

 **Children's Privacy**

We understand the importance of protecting children’s privacy in the interactive world. We are a general audience service and do not use the Services to knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of majority in your jurisdiction, including any information that requires parental notice and consent under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“ **COPPA** ”) without such parental consent.

If you are a child under the age of majority in your jurisdiction, you are not permitted to use the Services and should not send any information about yourself to us through the Services. In the event that we become aware that we have collected personal information from any child under the age of thirteen (13), we will dispose of that information in accordance with COPPA and other applicable laws and regulations. If you are a parent or guardian and you believe that your child under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information without COPPA-required consent, please contact us at (312) 876-0004 or send us an email at inquire@winsightmedia.com.  You may also contact us by postal mail or by fax, using the following: Winsight, LLC, 300 S. Riverside Plaza, Suite 1600, Chicago, IL 60606 Fax: (312) 876-1158.

* * *

 **Sensitive Personal Data**

We ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any sensitive personal data (for example, social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background or trade union membership) on or through the Services or otherwise to us.

If you send or disclose any sensitive personal data to us, we will treat it as Personal Data and you consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent to our processing and use of such sensitive personal data, you must not submit such data to our Services.

* * *

 **Changes**

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time in our discretion and will notify you of any material changes to the way in which we treat Personal Data, by posting a notice on relevant areas of the Services. We may also provide notice to you in other ways in our discretion, such as through contact information you have provided. Any updated version of this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy, unless otherwise specified. Your continued use of the Services after the effective date of the revised Privacy Policy (or such other act specified at that time) will constitute your consent to those changes. We will not, however, without your consent, use your Personal Data in a manner materially different than what was stated at the time your Personal Data was collected.

* * *

 **Contact Us**

Should you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please call us at (312) 876-0004 or send us an email at [inquire@winsightmedia.com](mailto:inquire@winsightmedia.com).  You may also contact us by postal mail or by fax, using the following: Winsight, LLC, 300 S. Riverside Plaza, Suite 1600, Chicago, IL 60606. The fax number is (312) 876-1158.

* * *

## [Data Protection Policy for EU Citizens](http://cspdigitals.com/winsight/Data-Protection-Policy-Winsight-LLC-052318-AY.pdf)

Last Revised: May 2018
